<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prerequisites on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/10_prerequisites.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prerequisites on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/10_prerequisites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/10_dynatrace.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/10_dynatrace.html</guid>
      <description>To complete the workshop, you first need a Dynatrace tenant to monitor AWS resources and completed the workshop exercises. Please choose the link from one of the following options:
Option 1: I need a Dynatrace tenant Navigate to Sign up for a 15-day trial
Option 2: I already have a Dynatrace tenant You will need admin rights to configure configuration rules and install agents. Ensure you have authority within your organization to do this in your tenant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for Dynatrace Trial</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/20_dynatrace_trial.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/20_dynatrace_trial.html</guid>
      <description>For this workshop you will use a 15-day free Dynatrace evaluation of the full feature set of our all-in-one performance monitoring platform. Once you sign up, you will be sent a confirmation email and it will then take about 5 minutes to provision your Dynatrace tenant.
Start free trial   While the tenant is provisioning, be sure to watch this short Dynatrace overview video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/30_azure.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/30_azure.html</guid>
      <description>To complete the workshop, you will also need an AWS subscription to complete the workshop exercises. Please choose the link from one of the following options:
Option 1: I have a Microsoft AWS Promo code To provision your subscription, navigate to Microsofts AWS Pass website
Using AWS Pass requires an email and the provisioning takes about 5 minutes to process.
 Option 2: I need an AWS subscription You can sign up for a free AWS trial account on the Microsofts website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Setup</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/40_workshop_setup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/40_workshop_setup.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, your will complete the following:
 Open AWS Cloud Shell for running various UNIX commands Capture environment and token info needed for automation scripts Provision easyTravel application Verify EasyTravel application is running  1. Open AWS Cloud Shell 1 . Navigate to https://portal.AWS.com/
2 . Click on the Cloud Shell button
If you get this prompt, choose bash
If you get this prompt, choose AWS Pass - Sponsorship and then click the Create Storage button.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>