<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adopt on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/40_adopt.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adopt on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/40_adopt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/10_identify.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/10_identify.html</guid>
      <description>EasyTravel is a monolithic Java application that as we saw earlier provides several web services like Booking, Authentication, and Journey.
Our overall goal at easyTravel is to breakout each of these backend services into seperate services. This will allow us to have seperate Continuous Integration (CI) pipelines to build and test each service independantly. By putting these service into Docker images, we gain the ability to deploy the service into modern platforms like Kubernetes using AWS managed services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/20_scale.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/20_scale.html</guid>
      <description>Due to the complexity and effort of refactoring a bunch of code, Henrik has decided to take a mixed cloud adoption strategy.
The intermediate step will be to support his developments efforts:
 Refactor the backend Java application to be packaged and served within a Docker image Rebuild relational in-memory Apache Derby database to Mongo  The final step be to put on AWS Kubernetes Service (AKS) and AWS Cosmos DB once the Cloud operations team has complete their certification of AKS and Cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/30_summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/30_summary.html</guid>
      <description>While migrating to the cloud, you want to evaluate if your migration goes according to the plan, whether the services are still performing well or even better than before, and whether your new architecture is as efficient as the blueprint suggested. Dynatrace helps you validate all these steps automatically, which helps speed up the migration and validation process.
Having the ability to understand service flows enables us to make smarter re-architecture and re-platforming decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>