<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Main Page on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Main Page on Dynatrace Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cleanup</title>
      <link>/100_wrapup/10_cleanup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/100_wrapup/10_cleanup.html</guid>
      <description>In order to prevent charges to your subscription we recommend cleaning up the infrastructure that was created. If you plan to keep things running so you can examine the workshop a bit more please remember to do the cleanup when you are done. It is very easy to leave things running in an AWS subscription, forget about it, and then accrue charges.
 Delete Service Principal The Dynatrace AWS monitor setup also made a Service Principal that is used to pull data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/10_dynatrace.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/10_dynatrace.html</guid>
      <description>To complete the workshop, you first need a Dynatrace tenant to monitor AWS resources and completed the workshop exercises. Please choose the link from one of the following options:
Option 1: I need a Dynatrace tenant Navigate to Sign up for a 15-day trial
Option 2: I already have a Dynatrace tenant You will need admin rights to configure configuration rules and install agents. Ensure you have authority within your organization to do this in your tenant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace OneAgent</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/10_dynatrace_oneagent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/10_dynatrace_oneagent.html</guid>
      <description>Dynatraces OneAgent provides the industry’s largest technology coverage, spanning cloud native to legacy environments in an all-in-one solution. OneAgent provides:
 A set of specialized processes that run on each monitored host. OneAgent collects metrics from the operating system it runs on and compares the metrics to performance metrics. The metrics are then reported to Dynatrace. Monitors technologies like Java, Node.js, .NET and more in greater detail by injecting itself into processes and monitors performance with code level insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/10_identify.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/10_identify.html</guid>
      <description>EasyTravel is a monolithic Java application that as we saw earlier provides several web services like Booking, Authentication, and Journey.
Our overall goal at easyTravel is to breakout each of these backend services into seperate services. This will allow us to have seperate Continuous Integration (CI) pipelines to build and test each service independantly. By putting these service into Docker images, we gain the ability to deploy the service into modern platforms like Kubernetes using AWS managed services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OneAgent Manual Install</title>
      <link>/120_more/10_agent_install.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/120_more/10_agent_install.html</guid>
      <description>OneAgent is responsible for collecting all monitoring data within your monitored environment. A single OneAgent per host is required to collect all relevant monitoring data—even if your hosts are deployed within Docker containers, microservices architectures, or cloud-based infrastructure.
The OneAgent can be automatically installed and rolled out through configuration management tools such as Chef, Puppet, Ansible, AWS extentions &amp;amp; AWS Resource Management (ARM) templates or by just including the download and install into any custom deployment script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify Operations</title>
      <link>/50_operate/10_simplify_operations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50_operate/10_simplify_operations.html</guid>
      <description>Migrating to the cloud means there are more moving pieces to monitor and manage. As we have learned, Dynatrace fully automates monitoring through OneAgent and the native integration with AWS.
Post-migration, Dynatrace’s deterministic AI engine, DAVIS, helps you run your applications smoothly, pinpointing production issues with root-cause information right at your fingertips. DAVIS leverages Smartscape dependency data, as well as the high-fidelity monitoring data from OneAgent. The AI can be fed with external events such as deployment or configuration change events from your CI/CD or deployment automation tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Dynatrace</title>
      <link>/20_introduction/10_why_dynatrace.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20_introduction/10_why_dynatrace.html</guid>
      <description>Meet Pravin, easyTravels CTO, who will share the teams approach migrating to AWS and why they choose Dynatrace as strategic partner for this journey.
Enterprise Cloud is underpinning our digital transformation At easyTravel, enterprise cloud brings a great deal of change for it is all:
 completely software driven (including the infrastructure). dynamic and built on a complex ecosystem of micro services and containers running at massive scale spanning across multiple cloud environments and data centers constantly changing at a pace faster than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Adoption Framework</title>
      <link>/20_introduction/20_cloud_adoption_framework.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20_introduction/20_cloud_adoption_framework.html</guid>
      <description>We at easyTravel have embraced AWS proven guidance found within the Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework that is designed to help create and implement the business and technology strategies necessary to succeed in the cloud.
The Cloud Adoption Framework provides us with the best practices, documentation, and tools that cloud architects, IT professionals, and business decision makers need to successfully achieve short-term and long-term objectives.
By leveraging Dynatrace we see the value in each phase:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace</title>
      <link>/100_wrapup/20_dynatrace.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/100_wrapup/20_dynatrace.html</guid>
      <description>You have a fully feature enabled 15 day Dynatrace trial, so keep using it to monitor and manage your infrastructure and applications!!
Here are resources to get your started:
 Learn more about your tenant and install more OneAgents Add other users to your tenant YouTube Videos More Support resources  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Davis Works</title>
      <link>/50_operate/20_how_davis_works.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50_operate/20_how_davis_works.html</guid>
      <description>Davis is Dynatrace’s AI engine that is purpose-built for today’s web-scale enterprise clouds. Davis analyzes complex dependencies, creates application topology dynamically and helps you in anomaly detection.
1. Intelligent anomaly detection
Problems in Dynatrace represent anomalies, i.e. deviations from a normal behavior or state. Such anomalies can be, for example, a slow service or a slow user login to an application. Whenever a problem is detected, Dynatrace raises a specific problem event indicating such an anomaly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review easyTravel</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/20_review_eztravel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/20_review_eztravel.html</guid>
      <description>1 . Open the AWS portal (http://portal.AWS.com) and open the Virtual Machine (VM) page. One way to do this is search for virtual machines
2 . Open the VM called workshop-ez-1. On the VM overview page, you can see that this is a Linux (ubuntu 18.04) host.
Dynatrace OneAgent In addition to installing easyTravel on this host, the AWS CLI was used to install the Dynatrace OneAgent AWS VM extension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/20_scale.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/20_scale.html</guid>
      <description>Due to the complexity and effort of refactoring a bunch of code, Henrik has decided to take a mixed cloud adoption strategy.
The intermediate step will be to support his developments efforts:
 Refactor the backend Java application to be packaged and served within a Docker image Rebuild relational in-memory Apache Derby database to Mongo  The final step be to put on AWS Kubernetes Service (AKS) and AWS Cosmos DB once the Cloud operations team has complete their certification of AKS and Cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for Dynatrace Trial</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/20_dynatrace_trial.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/20_dynatrace_trial.html</guid>
      <description>For this workshop you will use a 15-day free Dynatrace evaluation of the full feature set of our all-in-one performance monitoring platform. Once you sign up, you will be sent a confirmation email and it will then take about 5 minutes to provision your Dynatrace tenant.
Start free trial   While the tenant is provisioning, be sure to watch this short Dynatrace overview video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/30_azure.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/30_azure.html</guid>
      <description>To complete the workshop, you will also need an AWS subscription to complete the workshop exercises. Please choose the link from one of the following options:
Option 1: I have a Microsoft AWS Promo code To provision your subscription, navigate to Microsofts AWS Pass website
Using AWS Pass requires an email and the provisioning takes about 5 minutes to process.
 Option 2: I need an AWS subscription You can sign up for a free AWS trial account on the Microsofts website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host and Smartscape</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/30_review_eztravel-host.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/30_review_eztravel-host.html</guid>
      <description>Now lets review what the OneAgent automatically discovered using these various Dynatrace views:
 Host Smartscape Services and Service Flow Transactions and services Databases Technologies Host view  You should be on the host page, but if not, from the right hand menu in Dynatrace choose hosts then click on the host with the prefix of workshop-ez-1.
On host page, you will see basic infrastructure information for the host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>/40_adopt/30_summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40_adopt/30_summary.html</guid>
      <description>While migrating to the cloud, you want to evaluate if your migration goes according to the plan, whether the services are still performing well or even better than before, and whether your new architecture is as efficient as the blueprint suggested. Dynatrace helps you validate all these steps automatically, which helps speed up the migration and validation process.
Having the ability to understand service flows enables us to make smarter re-architecture and re-platforming decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>/50_operate/30_summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50_operate/30_summary.html</guid>
      <description>What makes Dynatrace truly special and unique is Davis. Davis is the deterministic AI engine that automatically detects problems for you and pinpoints the root cause and explains the business impact without needing any manual configurations.
AI-supported baselining on the migrated services allows for validating the success of the migration project from a performance, resource and cost perspective. Live performance insights into the full stack allows us to:
 Dynamically scale and implement auto-mitigation strategies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processes and Services</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/40_review_eztravel-process.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/40_review_eztravel-process.html</guid>
      <description>In the Smartscape view, we saw the visualizations of the relationships in vertical stack and as well as the relationships spatially. Now lets view the process and service tiers to see the relationships from a single entity.
Lets return back to the host page where we will explore each of the tiers for the VM. To get back there, from the right hand menu in Dynatrace choose hosts then click on the host with the prefix of workshop-ez-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Setup</title>
      <link>/10_prerequisites/40_workshop_setup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10_prerequisites/40_workshop_setup.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, your will complete the following:
 Open AWS Cloud Shell for running various UNIX commands Capture environment and token info needed for automation scripts Provision easyTravel application Verify EasyTravel application is running  1. Open AWS Cloud Shell 1 . Navigate to https://portal.AWS.com/
2 . Click on the Cloud Shell button
If you get this prompt, choose bash
If you get this prompt, choose AWS Pass - Sponsorship and then click the Create Storage button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Flow</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/50_review_eztravel_service_flow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/50_review_eztravel_service_flow.html</guid>
      <description>As just mentioned, Dynatrace understands your applications’ transactions from end to end. This transactional insight is visualized through Service flow, which illustrates the sequence of service calls that are triggered by each service request in your environment.
With Service flow, you see the flow of service calls from the perspective of a single service, request, or their filtered subset. Along with the specific services that are triggered, you can also see how each component of a request contributes to the overall response time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transactions and Services</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/60_review_eztravel-transactions_services.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/60_review_eztravel-transactions_services.html</guid>
      <description>Within Dynatrace, services can take the form of web services, web containers, database requests, custom services, and more. Services may in turn call other services such as web services, remote services, and databases services.
Web applications consist of web pages that are served by web servers and web containers, for example Tomcat. Web and mobile applications are built upon services that process requests like web requests, web service calls, and messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/70_review_eztravel-databases.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/70_review_eztravel-databases.html</guid>
      <description>Click on the Databases link in the Dynatraces left side menu to view the databases that OneAgent was able to automatically discover and instrument.
As mentioned early, easyTravel uses an Apache Derby embedded relational database, but we also setup a easyTravel VM that is running MongoDB in a docker container. So you should see both listed in the database view.
Review MongoDB Click on the Mongo database to open the database page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology View</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/90_review_eztravel-technologies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/90_review_eztravel-technologies.html</guid>
      <description>Click on the Technologies link on the left side menu within Dynatrace to view the technologies that OneAgent was able to automatically discover and instrument.
The workshop is somewhat limited, so here is an example from another environment.
How this helps This is another out the box feature that helps you understand what technologies are in your environment and with a heatmap presentation to what degree they exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Monitor</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/100_azure_monitor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/100_azure_monitor.html</guid>
      <description> In addition to monitoring your AWS workloads using OneAgent, Dynatrace provides integration with AWS Monitor which adds Infrastructure monitoring to gain insight even into serverless application scenarios.
How this helps </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/110_summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/110_summary.html</guid>
      <description>By just installing the OneAgent, we have now gained a detailed topological view of easyTravel from the both the infrastructure and application tiers and we are now ready to tackle our adoption to the cloud armed with the answers we need.
 Right Priority - We now understand the complexity and interdependency of services and components to the rest of the environment architecture Right-Sizing the environment - We now understanding which resources are required to move along with their required resource consumption patterns Best Migration Strategy - We now understand the the current end-to-end transactions through architecture and can choose the best migration strategy (rehost, refactor, rearchitect, rebuild)  Checklist In this section, you should have completed the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable a Problem</title>
      <link>/30_assessment/120_enable_problem.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/30_assessment/120_enable_problem.html</guid>
      <description>The easyTravel applicaiton has a feature to enable &amp;amp; disable problem patterns built into its codebase so that we can simulate problems.
To enable a problem that Davis will pickup on workshop-ez-1, just run these scripts in the AWS cloud shell that will find the IP address for your workshop-ez-1 instance and make the required HTTP REST call for the feature flag.
Best to run each problem pattern seperately so that it is easier to analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>